--------ED------------
バイバイ
Bye bye...
ごめんね　衿衣ちゃん
Sorry Erii-chan.
Don't worry.
大丈夫　きっとまた会えるから
We'll meet again.
バイバイ　またね
Bye bye!
See you again!
絆理ちゃん　元気でね
Banri-chan...
Take care.
響き合う願いが今覚醒めてく
脑海中回响着的愿望现已苏醒
譲れない未来のために
为了绝不可相让的未来
巡り逢う運命を超えたその先に
只因在超越命运的前方
この想い輝くから
这份思念正闪耀着光芒
ここじゃない未来に
在那并非归属的未来
想い託してみては
寄存着这份思念
強さの本当の意味を
继续寻找着那
搜し続けてた
强大的真正意义
ありのままの痛みを
将各种痛苦
受け入れるその意味を
全部承受的意义
明日へ走り続ける君に知った
是奔向明天的你告诉了我
巡りゆく景色が今流れてく
那眼前的景色现已过去
手繰り寄せた世界の先
那紧牵着双手的世界的前方
降り注ぐシグナルを躰で感じて
身体已感觉到其中所倾注的信号
解き放つ今全てを
此刻解放所有一切
Just truthin my heart
いつだって迷わないよ
无论何时都不应迷茫
消せない想いがあるから
因为有着无法磨灭的思念
解き明かす真実から瞳を逸らさずに
直视那已经揭开的真相
I'll reach the next stage to realize all.
確かな絆信じて
请相信这份羁绊
Banri-chan and I were in the same Child-error facility.
<Child Error>
絆理ちゃんと私は　同じ置き去りの施設にいたの
I was shy and had a hard time making friends,
私　人見知りで　友達もできなくて
but I became friends with her.
でも　絆理ちゃんとだけは仲良くなれたの
She would always talk to me telepathically.
<Telepathy>
いつも　精神感応でお話してくれてたの
But after she transferred to a different facility, I didn't hear from her for a while.
けど　別の施設に移されて
其れ切り
But these days, I can hear her voice again.
なのに　この頃また聞こえるの絆理ちゃんの声が
She's saying, "Help me."
助けてって
"I'm suffering."
とても苦しいって
But I don't know where she is. I don't know why she's suffering,
でも　どこにいるのか
どうしてそんなに苦しいのか
分からないの
I want to help her, but I can't do anything for her.
助けてあげたいのに
私　何もできないの
Don't worry.
大丈夫ですよ　お友達はきっと見つかります
Your friend will be found.
No, I will find her.
いえ　私が見つけて見せます
Since I'm Judgement, after all!
<Judgement>
なんでだって　風紀委員ですから
Uiharu-san...
初春さん
That's right.
<Judgement>
そうだよ　こう見えても初春は優秀な風紀委員なんだから
Uiharu is an excellent Judgement member, even though she might not look like it.
You didn't have to say it like that...
「こう見えても」は余計です
Sorry, it just slipped out.
あっ　ごめん　つい
So, please rest assured.
だから　安心してください
Thank you.
ありがとうなの
Aren't you tired from all the check ups?
検査で疲れてませんか
How about getting some rest?
少し休んだほうが
Oh I'm fine.
うん　大丈夫なの
You mean the Level Upper incident?
<Level Upper>
幻想御手事件って　あの
Yes.
はい　その犯人　木山春生の過去を知る機会があって
I had an opportunity to look into the perpetrator, Kiyama Harumi's, past.
That Edasaki girl came up in it.
さっきの枝先って子が　その中に
The Experiment of Induced Explosion for Understanding of Principles of Out of Control Ability...
「暴走能力の法則解析用誘爆実験」
To think that something like that was going on...
そんなものが行われていたなんて
If I remember right, an old man called Kihara was the leader.
確か　指揮をとっていたのは　木原とかいうお爺ちゃんって
Kihara?
木原？
You mean, Kihara Gensei?
まさか木原幻生
Who is that?
どなたですの
He's a scientist. Some even think of him as being famous
科学者よ　一部では有名なね
He's also the so called "Mad Scientist".
いわゆる　マッドサイエンティスト
He wouldn't have any reluctance conducting tests on humans.
あの人ならは　人体実験もやりかねないわね
I hear he's missing now.
今は消息不明だって話だけど
If that experiment was really conducted, then the children who became test subjects might be the cause of the Poltergeists.
その実験が本当だとしたら
<Poltergeist>
被験者の子供たちが　乱雑開放の原因かもしれないわね
What do you mean?
どういうことですの
I mean that those children have become Out of Control Ability Users.
その子たちが暴走能力者になってるってこと
What?
If I remember correctly, those children are still sleeping.
でも確か　あの子たちは今でも眠り続けてるって
What if their abilities are going out of control without their consciousness?
意識がないまま能力が暴走しているとしたら
No way...
そんな
So, if the Poltergeists weren't caused by any intentional interference, then they unconsciously caused it?
意図的な干渉ではなく
<Poltergeist>
無意識のうちに乱雑開放を起こしていると
It's a possibility.
可能性はあるわ
Where are they, now?
その子たちは今どうしてるの
After the incident, Antiskill searched
for them, but they couldn't find them.
<Antiskill>
事件後警備員が捜索したのですが
発見には至っておりませんの
I see.
そう　じゃ　まずは捜し出すのが先決ね
Well then, finding them should be at the top of our list.
The lucky color for today is pink.
今日のラッキーカラーはピンク
Looks like our fortune's looking good.
幸先いいわね
H-Hey, wait...
ちょ　ちょっと待ってください
じゃ何ですか　枝先さんは木山の元生徒で
So Edasaki-san is Kiyama's former student,
and you're saying Edasaki-san and the others are causing the Poltergeist?
<Poltergeist>
その枝先さんたちが　乱雑開放を起こしてるっていうんですか
Well yes, although it's still just a hypothesis.
ええ　まだ仮説ですけれど
We won't know anything until we find those children.
その子たちを見つけないことには　何も分からないわね
But how will we find them?
見つけるだってどうやるんです
Well...
それは
I see.
そうか　パソコンでパパっとやっちゃえばいいんだ
By using the computer, it should be a fairly easy!
After all, this is Uiharu's speciality!
初春の出番じゃん
Right, Uiharu?
ねえ　初春
Of course I will find them.
勿論搜します
I will. However,
搜しますけど
since you suspected Haruue-san, are you suspecting her friend as well?
春上さんの次は　その友達を疑うんですか
That's enough!
あんたいい加減にしなよ
Those children need help...
あの子たちが　助けを　求めてる
Onee-sama,
お姉様　随分と長湯ですのね
You sure are taking a long bath.
Oh, I was thinking about something.
あっ　ちょっと考え事してた
Fine then.
でしたらよろしいんですけど
And what about you?
あんたはどうなのよ
How about you make up with Uiharu-san?
初春さんと仲直りしないの
It's understandable that Uiharu got angry.
初春が怒るのも無理やりませんわ
However, I haven't done anything wrong as Judgement.
<Judgement>
ですが　私　風紀委員として間違ったことはしておりません
But Uiharu must be feeling like she was betrayed.
でも初春は　恐らく裏切られたように
Even so, she will surely understand me. That's why...
それでも　きっと分かってくれると
私
I believe in her.
信じてます
Don't just barge in like that saying all that good stuff!
って　さらりといいこと言いながら　入ってくるな
Hey! I had good timing, though, didn't I?!
今のは言っていいタイミングでは
うるさい
Shut up!
Here. A get well gift!
はい　お見舞いです
It's from an old Taiyaki shop in the 8th Academy District.
第八学区にある　老舗の鯛焼き屋さんなんですよ
From so far away?
そんなに遠くから
You'll know why I went all the way there when you try it!
食べれば分かります
This is the best Taiyaki in the Academy City!
これ　学園都市一の鯛焼きですから
Oh, the filling is all all bean paste.
あっ　全部粒餡ですよ　それ以外は邪道です
Anything else is just wrong.
Oh, they're still warm.
わっ　まだ暖かいの
Actually, that's my ability.
実は　それ　私の能力なんです
I can maintain the temperature of
things I'm in contact with like this.
こうやって 触っているものの温度を一定に保ってるんです
Since I can't hold anything too hot,
lukewarm is about the best I can do.
あんまり熱いものだと持てないから
生暖かいのが限界なんですけど
I haven't told Misaka-san and the others about this.
これ　御坂さんたちにも教えてないんですよ
It's my way of giving back.
お返しです
Because you told us your ability.
春上さんの能力も教えてもらったから
Uh... Umm...
えっ　えっと
It's delicious.
うん　おいしいの
It really is delicious.
やっぱりおいしいです
According to Kiyama's testimony, ten test subjects were used for human testing.
木山の供述によると
人体実験の被験者は十名
All of them were left in a vegetative state and taken
into different medical facilities within Academy City.
全員が植物状態となり
学園都市内の医療機関に分散して収容された
But they're missing, you say?
けどいないのね
Yes.
ええ　転院を繰り返していて
They kept transferring over and over again, and then we finally lost track of them.
途中足取りが途絶えているんですの
I see.
そっ
How about taking a break?
一息入れたらいかがですの
No need.
要りません
Oh? Where are you going?
あれ　どこ行くの
Oh, nowhere, really.
いいえ　別に
Hey, are you thirsty?
ねえ　喉渇かない
Well, I felt kinda uneasy just showing up...
いや　何か　顔を出しづらくて
True.
そうね　ちょっとぎくしゃくしちゃったもんね　私たち
Our relationship is a bit tense at the moment.
We have to find Edasaki-san.
枝先さん　見つけなきゃね
This is for Haruue-san,
春上さんのためにも　初春さんのためにも
for Uiharu-san,
and also for us.
でもって　私たちのためにも
That's right.
そうですね
Wonder who that is...
誰だろう
Hello, this is Misaka.
はい　御坂です
What?
Kiyama Harumi was released on bail?
木山春生が保釈
Yes.
ええ　例の実験に関して話を聞こうと拘置所に行ったの
I went to the prison to hear from her about that experiment.
That's when I found out.
そしたら
She was allowed out on bail after all the stuff she did?
あれだけのことをやっておいて 保釈が認められるんですか
I don't know all the details about it, but it seems so.
詳しい事情はわからないけど　そうみたいね
No way...
そんな
Looks like our thread connected to the children just got cut.
子どもたちに繋がる糸が切れたわね
Huh?
あれ　でも　確か木山って
If I remember correctly, Kiyama caused that
incident to try and help those children, right?
子どもたちを助けようとして　あんな事件起こしたんですよね
If that's the case, then why would she try to use them?
それなのに　その子たちを利用するってのは
That doesn't surprise me.
おかしくないでしょう
Since she used the students here who were hoping for abilities.
学生の能力への憧れさえも　利用したような女よ
No need.
要りません
Enough with your stubbornness.
瘦せ我慢も大概にしたら
Oh, I'm sorry.
あっ　すいません
Even you are working so hard, we have no clue about it yet.
初春さんがこれだけやっても　尻尾も掴めないなんてね
Not yet.
まだです
There should still be data we can go look into.
まだ辿れるデータがあるはずです
Hey that's...
ねえ　ちょっとそれ
Huh?
"The Possibility of Mass Occurrence of RSPK Syndrome due to Resonance of AIM Diffusion Field"
AIM拡散力場の共鳴による
RSPK症候群集団発生の可能性
Resonance?
共鳴？
That's right.
そうですの
It says the AIM diffusion field resonates among ability users with the same type of abilities.
同系統の能力者のAIM拡散力場同士が　共鳴するというんです
First, one of them receives interference from the Out of Control Ability User.
まず一人が暴走能力者に干渉され
Next, ability users of the same type resonate one after the other.
その後同系統の能力者が次々に共鳴していきますの
しかも　この同系統というのが曲者で
This same type aspect makes things difficult.
Huh?
For example, you, Onee-sama,
例えばお姉様の場合ですと
you have the ability to control electric and magnetic fields, right?
電場を操る能力と磁場を操る能力が含まれていますでしょう
That means, you would resonate with multiple ability users.
つまり　複数の能力者と共鳴しますの
Then...
それじゃ
The same can be said for the ten Child Errors who have gone missing.
<Child Error>
行方不明となっている十名の置き去りにも同じことが言えますの
If all of them use the Out of Control Ability,
もし全員が暴走能力を発動させたとしたら
it will have an effect on 78% of all the students.
その影響範囲は全学生の実に78パーセント
78%?
78パーセント？！
That means...
それって
A Poltergeist on that scale could destroy this city.
<Poltergeist>
この町が壊滅しかねない規模の乱雑開放が起こりますわ
However, this paper could be wrong.
けど　この論文が正しいとは
Look closely at the author.
執筆者をよくご覧になってください
Kihara Gensei!
はっ　木原幻生
I researched him, but as Telestina-san said,
his whereabouts are unknown.
この男についても調べたのですが
テレス·ティーナさんの言っていたとおり　消息不明ですの
All the research facilities related to him have been closed down.
関連する研究施設も　全て閉鎖されていますし
The data is scattered and lost as well.
データも散逸していますの
Anything bothering you?
どうかなさいました
No, nothing...
ううん　別に
Onee-sama!
あー　お姉様
激しすぎますの
That's too much!
As much as I'd like to know what kind of dream you're having...
どんな夢見てんのか
激しくつっこみたいところだが
I'm sorry.
ごめんね
All right.
よし　これで変装も完璧
My disguise is perfect!
All right.
Huh?
I might not need this since this place has no electricity.
電気もきてないじゃん　これ要らなかったの
No doubt.
間違いない　ここだ
This is the place.
As I expected, nothing gained.
やっぱ空振りか
Nothing is left.
何も残っていません
Yes. I'll be leaving.
ええ　引き上げます
Level 6
The one who
reaches
heaven's will
without the
body of a god
A Certain Scientific Railgun
Level6
以凡人之肉体
领悟天之意志者
That's...!
あいつ
It's you.
君か
Kiyama Harumi, as I thought!
やっぱり　木山春生
Any business for me—
何か用でも
You caused this incident too?
今回の事件もあんたの仕業なの
What will you do if that's the case?
だとしたらどうする
許す訳ないでしょう
Of course I won't forgive you!
Oh, hey! What the heck is this?
ちょっと　何これ
No choice then...
仕方ない
Well done.
やってくれるよ
You give an electric shock to the dead security.
死んでいたセキュリティに電気ショックとはな
I didn't intend to do that.
私だってそんなつもりじゃ
More importantly, what were you doing there?
それよりあんた あんな所で何してたの
Why are you released on bail?
保釈ってどういうこと
何が目的なの
What are you trying to do?
There are always scary girls who ride in my car asking me questions.
私の車に乗るお嬢さんは　みんな怖い顔で質問するんだな
Huh?
は
I'm sorry but you will have to leave the questions for later.
すまないが　質問なら後にしてくれ
Staff Entrance
Third New Hospital Wing
This is...
ここって
This way.
こっちだ
This is...
これは
You should know, after peeking into my memories.
私の記憶を覗いた君なら知っているだろう
My students.
私の　教え子たちだ
As I thought,
<Poltergeist>
やっぱり　乱雑開放を起こしていたのは　あんたなのね
you were the one causing the Poltergeists!
That's right.
そうだ
But,
けど　それには少し複雑な事情があってね
there's some complicated circumstances leading up to that.
Also,
それと　すまないがここは病院なんでね
I'm sorry but, this is a hospital so...
電撃は遠慮してもらえないかな
could you refrain from using electrical shocks?
You're the guy from that time.
あっ　あの時の
Long time no see.
久しぶりだね
What in the world is going on?
一体何がどうなってるのよ
Kihara Gensei...
木原幻生
He is the cause of all this.
彼が全ての始まりなんだね
I shall ask this right here, then.
あえて問いましょう
What is our final goal?
我々の究極の目的とは何か
What is the reason Academy City exists?
学園都市が存在する理由とは何であったのか
That's right.
Creation of Level 6
<Level 6>
そう　人類を超えた存在絶対能力者を創造にほかなりません
An existence beyond humans...
is nothing other than the creation of Level 6.
A signal transfer circuit different from normal is created within the brain of an Out of Control Ability User.
暴走能力者の脳内では　通常とは異なるシグナル伝達回路が形成され
Various neurotransmitters and hormones are secreted at abnormal rates.
隠しの神経伝達物質
様々なホルモンが異常分泌されています
By collecting, concentrating, and
distilling the secreted substances,
それら分泌物質を採取し　凝縮生成したものこそ
this Ability Body Crystal was created.
この能力体結晶なのです
By prescribing this to certain chosen ability users, Level 6 can be created.
これを特に選ばれた能力者に溶いをすることによって
<Level 6>
絶対能力者を生み出せるんです
The Ability Body Crystal is the torch of science.
能力体結晶こそ　長らく暗闇にとらされていた
It shall illuminate the path long covered in darkness.
神ならぬ身にして天上の意志に辿り着くもの
Systen - The one who reaches heaven's will without the body of a god.
システムへと至る道を照らし出す　科学の灯火なのです
Would something like that really create Level 6?
あんなもので
<Level 6>
本当に絶対能力者が作り出せるもんですかな
Of course.
勿論だと思う
Really?
本当かい
It would needlessly cause consciousness issues and may have severe side effects, right?
いたずらに意識障害を招き　重篤な副作用を起こすのではないかなぁ
The experiments are showing steady progress.
実験は着実に成果を上げている
How much sacrifice was needed for that?
そのために  どれだけの犠牲を払ったんだい
Sacrifice?
犠牲？私の研究に犠牲者などいない
There are no sacrifices in my research.
Of course there aren't.
いるわけがない
I don't know how he perceived them, but sacrifices did exist.
彼がその存在をどう認識していたかは知らないが
犠牲者はいたんだよ
After getting involved with that incident and understanding what lead up to it,
あの実験に関わり　事の経緯を知り
そして　確信したんだ
Kiyaha Harumi Testimony 01
I came to the conclusion.
The Child Errors Kiyama-kun was trying to "help" were simply test subjects for the Ability Body Crystal.
<Child Error>
木山君が救おうとしていた置き去りが
能力体結晶の実験体にされたんだってね
The "Experiment of Induced Explosion...
あの時君に話した
for Understanding of Principles of Out of Control Ability" I talked about was just a cover-up.
「暴走能力の法則解析用誘爆実験」すらも方便だったんだ
What you saw was the prescription testing of Ability Body Crystals!
君の見たあれは　能力体結晶の登用実験だ
No way...
<Level 6>
そんな　絶対能力者なんて　取っ掛かりも見つかってないようなもののために
For something like Level 6 which we don't even have any idea about?
For some crazy experiment,
そんないかれた実験のせいで  この子たちはこんなにされたっていうの
you're saying these children were screwed like this?
As a doctor, all I can do is to try to save these children.
僕にできるのは　医者としてこの子たちを救うことだけだ
Fortunately, it didn't take too long to gather all of them.
幸い全員を集めるのにそう時間はかからなかった
I still have some power within this city.
僕はこの町では多少顔が利くからね
I only wanted to hear from the specialist before I woke them up.
後は目覚めさせるために　専門家の話が聞きたくて
That's why you asked for bail?
それで保釈を
I was the one who insisted.
無理を言ったのは私のほうだ
I am grateful to you, Doctor.
先生には感謝している
Thanks to you I was able to use the facilities here,
ここの設備を使えたおかげで
and now I have a chance to wake these children up.
この子たちを目覚めさせる目処が付いた
So, will they be saved?
じゃ　助かるの
No, a different problem has occurred.
いや　別の問題が発生したんだね
A problem?
問題？
When they got close to waking up, the AIM diffusion field went beyond normal limits.
覚醒が近づくと　AIM拡散力場が異常値を示した
That means...
それって
Ability going out of control.
能力の暴走だ
It also caused the mass simultaneous occurrence of RSPK syndrome.
そしてRSPK症候群の同時多発を引き起こした
Why?
なんで
His research seems to have actually been progressing.
彼の研究は進んでいたんだね
The Ability Body Crystal I knew about wouldn't have ever have caused poltergeist.
僕の知っていた能力体結晶では
<Poltergeist>
乱雑開放など起こるはずがなかったんだよ
However, the Ability Body Crystal
which had been developed further...
だが 改良を加えられた能力体結晶は
Changed these children into Out of Control Ability Users while they were still asleep.
この子たちを眠りながらにして　暴走能力者にしてしまっていた
That means, when they try to wake up...
じゃ　この子たちが目を覚まそうとすると
Yes.
<Poltergeist>
ああ　乱雑開放が起こる
Poltergeist happens.
Is there any other way?
何か　方法はないの
I am developing a vaccine software that should suppress the condition.
暴走を鎮めるワクチンソフトを開発している
However, the core of the Ability Body Crystal is called First Sample.
ただ　能力体結晶の根幹を成しているのはファーストサンプルと呼ばれる
It's substance was extracted from the first human test subjects.
最初期の人体実験の被験者から生成された成分だ
To complete the vaccine software its data needs to be analyzed, no matter what.
ワクチンソフトを完成させるには
どうしてもそのデータの解析が必要なんだ
So you were at that lab to...?
もしかして　さっきの研究所にいたのは
I was looking for that data.
そのデータを探していた
Nothing was left though.
何も残されてはいなかったわね
But I can't give up.
だが諦められるものか
That data is essential for Ability Body Crystal research.
あのデータは能力体結晶の研究に必要不可欠なものだ
There's no way it would have been discarded.
それだけのものが廃棄されるはずがない
It's got to be somewhere.
どこかに必ず
I will find it no matter what!
私は　どんなことをしても見つけ出してみせる
What will you do if you can't find it?
もし　見つからなかったら
I will wake these children.
この子たちは覚醒させる
Knowing Poltergeists will happen?
<Poltergeist>
乱雑開放が起きるのを承知の上で
I can't keep them asleep any longer!
これ以上この子たちを眠らせてはおけない！
Even so...!
だからって
That's...
そんな
That's right. We won't let that happen.
そう　そんなことはさせない
Telestina-san.
テレス·ティーナさん
I'm sorry.
ごめんね　あとをつけさせてもらったわ
I followed you.
What are you...
一体
the Multi Active Rescue.
精神状況救助隊です
We will be protecting these children.
子供たちを保護します
Please obey our orders obediently.
おとなしく我々に従ってください
Is that an order?
それは命令か
Yes.
ええ　レスキューとして
As part of Rescue, we will stop anything
that would cause damage to Academy City.
学園都市に被害が出る事態は 断固阻止します
We have a warrant but,
令状も用意しましたが
as for me, I would like you to volunteer to hand them over.
私としては　自発的に引き渡していただけることを望みます
It seems to be real.
本物のようだね
Rest assured.
安心してください
We are specialists in saving lives.
我々は人命救助のスペシャリストです
We have facilities prepared to protect and treat ability users.
能力者を保護し　治療するための設備は整っています
But...
しかし
Data that you can not access, we can legally access.
あなたにアクセスできないデータも 我々であれば合法的にアクセスできます
There is a high possibility we can get a hold of the First Sample data you were talking about.
今のお話にあったファーストサンプルのデータも
入手できる可能性が高いのです
Protect them.
保護しろ
Wait!
待て
What is that for?
何の真似だ
You're the one who told me to get in the way if you disagree.
気に入らなければ邪魔をしろと言ったのは　あなたでしょう
Out of my way!
退け　あの子たちを救えるのは私だけなんだ
I'm the only one who can save them!
You're failing!
救えてないじゃない
You used the Level Upper,
<Level Upper>
幻想御手を使って
you caused Poltergeists,
<Poltergeist>
乱雑開放を起こして
But you haven't saved even one!
でも　一人も救えてない
Just a little more...
あと少し　あと一息なんだ
There's just a little more left to do.
So...
だから
Edasaki-san is crying out for help right now.
枝先さんは　今助けを求めているの
Haruue-san, my friend...
春上さんが　私の友達が
she hears her voice.
彼女の声を　聞いているのよ
Send them out.
運び出せ
狙い定めた指先が指す
運命は絶望 それとも希望
A Certain Scientific Railgun
To be continued
待
续
ゆらぎの中で受信してゆく
悲しみにも負けない
勇気だけをください
大切なもの　守るため
「強さ」があると信じてる
Saving our future 一緒に
明日へのドア開いた空へ飛び立とう
とある世界の果てで
駆け抜けてくReal Force
光を放って
Doing the preview again after so long makes me nervous.
Next Episode
久々の予告は緊張する
What are you
seeing with your eyes
right now?
现在你眼中
能看见什么？
No choice then. I should undress.
仕方ない　脱ごう
So then next episo—
さて次回
Hey! Learn how to read the atmosphere!
で　いい加減空気読もうよ もうクライマックスなんだからさ
It's the climax already!